Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia 5034 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia
1884-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA)
5034 MB
3.86 cubic feet
3.9 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia including badges, buttons, bandana, plaques, certificates and other miscellaneous items
5919187
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 04, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Switchmen's Union of North America is among the older of the railway brotherhoods. Beginning in 1877 with the formation of a local Switchmen's organization in Chicago, the movement became national when the Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America held its first meeting nine years later.
This association was destroyed, as a result of a disastrous lockout by the Chicago Northwestern and the 1888 strike against the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy which had equally unfortunate results. Building on what was left of the S.M.A.A., several lodges met in Kansas City in October of 1854 and formed the Switchmen's Union of North America.
By the time of its merger into the United Transportation Union in 1969, the single Chicago labor organization of 1877 had grown to international status with 275 lodges in the United States and Canada having a combined membership of 12,000.
CHRONOLOGY
1877 Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America organized
1886 Switchmen's Association organized
1889 Switchmen's Association affiliated with the Supreme Council of United Orders of Railway Employees
1894 Switchmen's Association dissolved in July
Switchmen's Union of North America organized on October 13
1906 Switchmen's Union of North America affiliated with the American Federation of Labor
1926 Switchmen's Union of North America becomes charter member of the Railway Labor Executives Association
1935 Switchmen's Union of North America affiliated with the Canadian Labor Congress
1969 Switchmen's Union of North America joined with the B.R.T., B.L.F. and E., and O.R.C.B. to form the United Transportation Union
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5034: Switchmen's Union of North America Records 5034 P: Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs 5084: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5405 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Constitutions on Microfilm 5406 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on Microfilm 5447: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Unification Minutes and Convention Proceedings 5556: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5556 AV: Switchmen's Union of North America Audio-Visual Materials 5590: Switchmen's Union of North America Lake Shore Lodge 55 Membership Registers 5613: Switchmen's Union of North America Oakland Lodge 158 Meeting Minutes 5630: W.B. Meyers Papers
Switchmen's Union of North America; Switchmen's Union of North America--Collectibles
5919187
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badge, buttons, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Badge- "Conductor" for "Chicago, Lodge, No. 199, S.U. of N.A., Chicago, Ill." (two sided) side two is a "In Memoriam" [side one is green, red & white, side two is black]; badge-"St. Columba's, Rosary and Altar Society" (also two sided, with side two
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Badge- For "Chicago, Lodge, No. 199, S.U. of N.A., Chicago, Ill." (two sided) side two is a "In Memoriam" [side one is green, red & white, side two is black] - one for "Past President" one for "Vice President" and one for "President"
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Badge- For "Chicago, Lodge, No. 199, S.U. of N.A., Chicago, Ill." (two sided) side two is a "In Memoriam" [side one is green, red & white, side two is black] - one for "Treasurer" one for "Secretary" and one for "Board of Directors"
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Badge- For "Chicago, Lodge, No. 199, S.U. of N.A., Chicago, Ill." (two sided) side two is a "In Memoriam" [side one is green, red & white, side two is black] - one for "Outside Guard" one for "Inside Guard" and one for "Chaplain"
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Badge - "Guest" (one with slot for name) - "Twenty-Sixth Regular Session Seventh Quadrennial Convention Switchmen's Union of North America, AFL-CIO, Buffalo, N.Y., July 15-20 1963"
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges & buttons, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Badge - (with slot for name) - "Twenty-Sixth Regular Session Seventh Quadrennial Convention Switchmen's Union of North America, AFL-CIO, Buffalo, N.Y., July 15-20 1963"; "Guest S.U. of N.A., 6th Quadrennial Convention1959" & "Guest" for "7th Quadren
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges & buttons (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Badges - "Member" for "Maple Leaf, Lodge No. 84, Switchmen's Oelwein, IA" (two sided, side two is "In Memoriam"); push pins - oval pins for "Roll of Honor Member"; "SU of NA" (one gold, one white); gold with "Switchmen's Union of North America"
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges (Box 1, Folder 8)
  badges - two sided each with side two being "In Memoriam"; side ones - "Maple Leaf Lodge No. 84, Switchmen'sOelwein, IA."; "Sedalia Lodge No. 20 S.U. of N.A., Sedalia, Missouri"; "M.J. Naughton Lodge, No.11, Switchmen'sCleveland, Ohio"
- Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA) - badges, Employer's Certificate, pins, 1921-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  "Constitution of Twin City District Council"; "Employer's Certificate"; badges - "5th Triennial Convention, Switchmen's Buffalo, N.Y., 1930", "Delegate" for "Toledo, Ohio, May 1921", "S.U. of N.A., International Convention, June 9, 1941"; "Seal of
- A.F.L.-C.I.O. SUNA: buttons, pen pins, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Buttons - [black w/gold leaves] "AFL-CIO, Switchmen's1962"; "SU of NA Member"; "Switchmen's, AFL-CIO 1966"; "Switchmen's Union"; "Switchmen'sS.U. for U, Join Now"; "We Like Our Independence, Join S.U. of N.A."; pen buttons - "Switchmen's...
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Buttons - "A.F.L. [month] SUNA [year]" - assorted colors,
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1918-1920 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Buttons - "A.F.L. [month] SUNA [year]" - assorted colors; "Switchmen's Union174"
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Buttons - "A.F.L. [month] SUNA [year]" - assorted colors
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- A.F.L./SUNA - buttons, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- A.F.L.-C.I.O./Switchmen's Union of North America - buttons, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Buttons - "A.F.L. C.I.O. [month] [year] Switchmen's Union of North America" - assorted colors; one button, black with gold lettering/gold leaves, "AFL-CIO, Switchmen's Union of North America, 1962"
- A.F.L.-C.I.O./Switchmen's Union of North America - buttons, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Buttons - "A.F.L. C.I.O. [month] [year] Switchmen's Union of North America" - assorted colors; button, green with white lettering, "AFL-CIO, Switchmen's Union of North America, Our 69th Year 1894-1963""
- A.F.L.-C.I.O./Switchmen's Union of North America - buttons, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Buttons - "A.F.L. C.I.O. [month] [year] Switchmen's Union of North America Serving Switchmen since 1894" - assorted colors
- A.F.L.-C.I.O./Switchmen's Union of North America - buttons, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Buttons - "A.F.L. C.I.O. [month] [year] Switchmen's Union of North America" - assorted colors (many duplicates); "Join SU of NA, The Switchmen's Choice"; "We Like Our Independence, Vote S.U. of N.A.", "The Switchmen's Choice"
- Switchmen's Union of North America - bandanna and arm band (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Red bandanna owned by Dan Collins, black arm band worn by union member.
- SUNA wooden plaque (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Wooden plaque, black with gold lettering - "International Union of S U of N A"
- SUNA glass plate (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Smoked glass plate with gold and red lettering, and design, "Switchmen's Union of North America", "Organized Oct. 23, 1894"
- Miscellaneous keys (railroad); Rubber stamp (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Gold keys - stamped with lettering "L. & N.R.R."; Rubber stamp lettered "Switchmen's Union of North America"
- SU of NA, AFL-CIO - Constitution and By-Laws, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  "Constitution and By-Laws, S.U. of N.A., A.F.L.-C.I.O." for both 1959 and 1963
- SUNA - membership cards, pay rate information, train routes, rail passes, 1902-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Orange - "Official Card"; green - "Delegate's Credential" card; pink and yellow - "Rates of Pay - Yard Service" cards; schedule of pay for "Leadville Yard, July 1901"; "CH Beegle's train routes"; railway passes from "Lake Shore and Michigan Southern
- SUNA - certificates, 1892-1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Certificate of membership for SUNA to the "National Fraternal Congress of America" (1945); Official commendation from "US Treasury" for the operation of the payroll savings plan (Buffalo Lodge 266); Insurance certificate from Switchmen's Mutual Aid Asso
- SUNA - bumper stickers (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Bumper stickers - black and orange "VOTE for Switchmen's Union of N.A."
- SUNA - cartoons, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Cartoons - 1959 cartoon about feather-bedding by member of SUNA Local 157; cartoon captions on others - "A Democratic Union!"; "A Growing Union"; "In the Interests of Switchmen"; "Improved working conditions, higher wages, safety"; "A Better Deal"
- SUNA - decals, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  SUNA decals/stickers - black, red, green, white with SUNA symbol in center and "Organized Oct. 23, 1894" on bottom
- SUNA - receipt books, 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  "Official" receipt books for SUNA (1953-1957).
- SUNA - Cypher Code books (2nd edition, 1907) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Cypher Code books for No. 283, Buffalo, NY, January 1, 1907 and Times Press (2nd edition)
- SUNA - Ritual books, 1924-1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Ritual books (1924 & 1951) - "Ritual of the Switchmen's Union of North America"
- SUNA - Convention, souvenir books, 1909-1941 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Convention booklets - Souvenirs from the following conventions - "Twenty-First Regular and Second Quadrennial, International Convention"; "Fourth Biennial Convention"; "Twentieth Regular and First Quadrennial, International Convention"; "Eighteenth Int
- SUNA - Miscellaneous memorabilia, 1884-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Schematic diagram of engine parts; Design plans & sample button, 1963, with instructions to manufacture; Invitation to Grand Annual Ball of the Switchmen's Mutual Aid Assoc. of Chicago, Dec. 23, 1884; Propaganda "Attention Erie-Lackawanna Switchmen
- SUNA - black ball box (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Wooden black ball box used for initiation, white and black marbles included inside box
- Banner (Box 5)
  - Banner: International Lodge Switchmen's of North Union America AFL-CIO; (Switchmen's Symbol in the center of banner) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    White felt with red trim and green lettering, gold tassels hang from support rod at each end of banner; 46" x 110"
  - SUNA - banner [oversize area, rolled/wrapped] (Box 5, Folder 1)
    [Felt - white w/red trim and lettering, gold tassels] - "International Lodge, Switchmen's Union of North America, AFL-CIO"
- Winter scene; train in background [3-oil painting]; Lorenzo Coffin burial hut historic certificate (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 7)